four things i like about the rogue tb2
trap bar or the fully knurled handles
you can flip it over to increase your
range of motion the loading sleeves are
16 inches long which is what you'll find
on the majority of barbells and it's
also rackable which is going to add to
its versatility i've been using this
trap bar for quite a while so today
i'm gonna break down all my findings for
you guys
[Music]
what's up everybody it's jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
review locked and loaded ready to go for
y'all this time it's the rogue tb2 trap
bar in this video i'm going to take you
through everything you need to know
about this trap bar from the price and
the features some pros and cons that
i've experienced and of course who
should or maybe should not add this to
their home gym
but before i get going i have to let you
know we've reviewed a lot of trap bars
on barbin.com if you want to browse our
best list just go ahead and search
barbend best trap bars and you can find
out for yourself which ones that we like
the best
okay so what do i like about the tb2
trap bar well i really like the knurling
on these handles it gives me a sticky
tack like grip it's going to be really
nice as you go to load up for some super
heavy deadlifts this is also a really
good option for any beginners out there
also people who are rehabbing from an
injury
because if you use these raised handles
right here it's going to decrease your
range of motion and allow you to
properly learn how to dead lift which
will really come into effect as you
start throwing on some heavy weight and
you make sure that your form is exactly
how it needs to be but as you get the
hang of it you know as you start feeling
good about everything you can also flip
this trap bar over use these handles
down here and that's going to increase
your range of motion a lot of people
deadlift with barbells but i personally
think that a trap bar is the superior
choice your body's aligned more
naturally with these handles and your
shoulders and you know a lot of issues
people run into with trap bars though is
that the loading sleeves are shorter
than what they are on a barbell well
that's not the case here these loading
sleeves are 16 inches long which is
pretty much what you're gonna find on a
barbell you know give or take half an
inch or so and plus this is a rackable
trap bar which is pretty unique it's
gonna add to its versatility you can use
this thing for shoulder presses maybe
even a bench press if you want to with a
power rack
[Music]
okay so there really aren't too many
issues with the tb2 but there's still a
couple things that i definitely should
mention so
i personally like the knurling right
here as i said but it is pretty abrasive
it might be too abrasive for some people
i personally think that's a good thing
you know as you're loading up some heavy
weight for a deadlift you obviously want
to be able to hang on to this bar and
that's going to allow you to do so but
once again you know could be too
abrasive could tear up some people's
hands so keep that in mind as you're
changing your weight plates
you might notice that some of the paint
you know wears off on the loading
sleeves i've read some reviews about
that online this has a powder coat
finish i personally have not experienced
that yet but
definitely could happen so you also want
to keep that in mind another thing here
that's probably the biggest issue is
that
these loading sleeves are not compatible
with every single weight collar bumper
plate weight plate out there
so
my weight collars simply just slide off
they don't really clamp onto the bar so
you might want to keep that in mind
you're most likely going to have to go
out and get some rogue you know specific
plates and weight collars that are
compatible with this trap bar the
handles are 25 inches apart on top and
the bottom i personally think that's
fine i think the majority of people are
going to be able to lift with this no
problem but if you are a little bit
smaller you know you could run into the
issue that these are a little bit you
know too spaced out for you
in that case you know i don't really
know a good solution for you it might
just be something you have to work
around so definitely want to keep that
in mind as well and once you tack on
shipping and taxes this is going to cost
you right around
and you know at the end of the day it's
a trap bar yeah this one's pretty
versatile it is rackable you can
technically do some bench presses and
shoulder presses with it but you know
what's more versatile than a trap bar a
barbell you can definitely get one for
500 even less so definitely keep that in
mind as well too
[Music]
okay so in terms of pricing the tb2 is
listed around 400 bucks but once you
tack on shipping and taxes
you're gonna be looking at spending over
500 on this trap bar i know that's kind
of expensive but you know remember it is
coming from rogue obviously they're
known for their high quality products
that's no exception here and you know
once you get this thing in your hands
you can definitely tell you're getting
that high quality so you know if you're
somebody out there looking for a
specialty bar you're really wanting to
you know focus on your deadlifts the
proper way
i think this could be worth the money
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
with the tb2 and some of the features
that you'll find so starting with the
handles you know these are 1.3 inches in
diameter the top handle is not fully
knurled but the bottom one is which is
really cool in my opinion you can kind
of grab it really wherever you want as
long as it's not gonna you know
teeter-totter on you as you're working
out but that knurling is really nice it
feels really solid in your hands it's
going to give you a really good grip and
remember all you have to do to utilize
the other handles is just simply flip it
over whichever way you have it just flip
it and you can use the other side the
loading sleeves are 16 inches long and
they're 1.9 inches in diameter and the
square steel tubing right here is 1.5
inches in diameter so this is a really
solid build it's really sturdy and once
again it's really evident once you get
it in your hands the handles are also 25
inches apart from one another i think
that's a really solid distance for the
majority of weight lifters and from the
ground to the top of these raised
handles they're 8.25 inches off the
ground this is a rackable trap bar i'll
show you guys how to do that here in a
little bit
and you know this is 88 and a half
inches long and it weighs 60 pounds so
you're gonna feel that whenever you pick
it up too you can definitely do some
farmers walks and maybe even some lunges
different things with just the bar you
don't necessarily have to load on weight
if you don't want to now in terms of
overall weight capacity i don't really
know that number so i reached out to
rogue and really all they told me was
just you know load that bad boy up you
know throw whatever you can at it and it
can handle it now i know i personally am
not gonna be able to max this trap bar
out
a lot of you probably can't either but
there's definitely some of y'all that
absolutely can and first of all i'm
pretty jealous of you but anyways you
know since i do not know that exact
number just keep that in mind and be
careful
all right guys let's do a quick walk
around with this trap bar let's start
with the loading sleeves as you can see
i do not have a rogue plate on here
right now and there's a bit of a wobble
obviously that's something you don't
want to happen if you were to drop this
you run into the issue the possibility
should i say of damaging your weight
plates bumper plates and that's
something you really don't want to
happen now let's slide this off and i
don't even have a rogue weight collar
right here
obviously you can see this is already
clamped shut i'll have to do this and
just slide right on so this definitely
is not compatible with that 1.9 inch
diameter
and you know there's a little bit of
wearing away of the the paint right here
you know this is a powder coat finish
it's not too bad yet but you know maybe
over time i'll experience that like i've
seen online like i was talking about
earlier now if we come further down you
will see this is that 1.5 inch square
steel tubing
super sturdy in my hands i know it's
welded together but it really doesn't
feel like that it feels like one solid
piece of steel which
obviously is a very nice touch i really
like these raised handles you know once
again they're 8.25 inches off the ground
it's gonna be really ideal for anybody
looking to learn the proper technique
when dead lifting and this is that
knurling i was talking about it's pretty
aggressive it's pretty abrasive but it
feels really good in my hands at the
same time you know kind of reminds me of
a power bar and to use these other
handles down here just simply flip the
bar over it's
easy done it's pretty easy to do that
once again you know this is 88 and a
half inches long and it weighs 60 pounds
on its own
and trust me you will feel that weight
when you go to pick it up you can
absolutely implement some exercises with
just the weight of this trap bar and be
just fine you'll still get a nice burn
in with that workout now don't forget
this is a rackable trap bar so look i'm
gonna show you how to do that right now
simply toss that on there and you can
flip it over like this and you can rep
out some bench presses and even do some
shoulder presses if you choose to do so
[Music]
okay so who should purchase the rogue
tb2 trap bar well i personally think
trap bars are the ideal choice when it
comes to learning the proper technique
when it comes to deadlifting
specifically this one right here because
of the raised handles so if you are a
beginner or maybe you're rehabbing an
injury i think you're really going to
enjoy this because it's going to
decrease the required range of motion
that you need and then you know
obviously once you get comfortable and
get that proper technique
definitely just flip this over and
increase that range of motion by
utilizing these other handles so that's
pretty cool and if you're looking for
you know a really versatile trap bar
this is right at the top of the list of
versatile trap bars because it's able to
be racked into a power rack or a squat
rack if you have one so you can
definitely use this for shoulder presses
and even a bench press if you want to
i will say though in my opinion you know
nothing gets it done like good old
trusty set of dumbbells or even a
barbell but you know if you want to do
that with this you absolutely can
and you know also anybody who's just
really wanting to load on a bunch of
weight plates on either side you can
definitely do that you know a lot of
trap bars feature loading sleeves that
are around 13 inches long and you kind
of run out of room that's really not the
case here these are 16 inches long
very comparable to a barbell
so yeah you can definitely pack on those
weight plates
who might not want to purchase the tb2
well
it's expensive right not everybody's
going to want to spend 500 on a trap bar
because at the end of the day it's a
trap bar yeah this one's pretty
versatile
but so is a barbell like i said you can
get one of those for the same price
actually maybe even cheaper so this
really is geared towards somebody who's
you know looking for a specialty bar and
really wants to focus on their deadlifts
the loading sleeves are not going to be
compatible with every single weight
collar and weight plate out there so if
you don't have any rogue equipment
already you either need to invest in
some or probably just look elsewhere
four different trap bars so you might
want to keep that in mind as well and
the handles you know once again these
are 25 inches apart
the majority of people should be able to
work out with this just fine but you
know obviously there's people of smaller
stature who are gonna want something
that is closer together and you might be
able to find that elsewhere online but
you know obviously that's not the case
here well that's all she wrote for the
rogue tb2 trap bar i personally love
this thing i love working out with it
it's really versatile you know i can
throw it on my power rack and really rep
out some shoulder presses and even bench
presses if i really want to this is a
great option for beginners and anyone
rehabbing an injury to learn the proper
technique of a deadlift you know you're
naturally aligned with your body and the
handles which is a really nice touch but
since these are elevated it's going to
decrease your range of motion so you can
absolutely learn that proper technique
it's also going to decrease the amount
of stress on your lower back which is
really nice touch but once again to
increase your range of motion all you do
is flip this bad boy over and that's it
you can increase it in a matter of
seconds which is really cool
now remember the knurling here is pretty
abrasive which might not be ideal for
everybody and these handles are 25
inches apart which once again might not
be ideal for every single person out
there wanting to use this
the loading sleeves
are likely not compatible with your
equipment you have at home unless you
have rogue equipment already no weight
collars weight plates bumper plates
whatever
if you don't though you're gonna
definitely have to invest because you
know stuff i have doesn't really fit
with this so it could be a bit of an
issue for a lot of people at the end of
the day though this is a solid piece of
equipment i really think it could be a
really nice addition for anybody who has
a more advanced home gym thanks for
watching everybody i hope this video was
really helpful and i was able to answer
any questions you might have about the
tv2 as always stay on the lookout for my
next review but for now head over to
barbin.com and you can read more about
this trap bar just search barbind rogue
tb2 trap bar review and you'll find all
the details that we talked about here
today i'll see y'all next time
[Music]
you